Contact

lukesterrett8@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/lukesterrett-3628101ba (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

Ruby on Rails React.js Node.js

Luke Sterrett

Senior Ruby/React Developer Albany

Summary

I am a highly skilled and very language-flexible web developer with 7+ yrs of experience in responsive web development with Ruby, Ruby on Rails, React, Angular, Vue, Node, Express, Next, Tailwind, Material, Bootstrap, RESTful API, GraphQL, MongoDB, PostgreSQL, etc. My work experience runs the gamut of software development, from software architecture, database design to website/webapp development.

Tech Stacks:

- Ruby, Ruby on Rails, Sinatra, Hanami
- React, Angular, Vue, Next, Node, Express, Tailwind, Material, Bootstrap, jQuery
- RESTful API, GraphQL, 3rd party API integration
- MongoDB, PostgreSQL, MySQL

I am a proven troubleshooter who works well with other team members and I have worked with Agile Development, building test-driven code both as a developer and as a scrum master. In my personal life, I enjoy spending time with friends and family, as well as almost any outdoor activity.

Experience

Bentley & Hoke

Software Engineering (Ruby on Rails, React, Angular, Node)
January 2018 - March 2021 (3 years 3 months)

Syracuse, NY, United States

 Pioneered the first comprehensive React front-end site generation framework in the Deno ecosystem for creating scalable Ruby on Rails applications that can be transformed into minified rendered pages for improved SEO and deployability

- Wrote a memoized recursive algorithm to traverse React.js' component dependency tree, optimize build performance, and generate components in the appropriate reference order
- Created a comprehensive CLI to walk developers through the initial setup of a Vno SSG boilerplate application
- Involved in the development of Web Services using SOAP for sending and getting data from the external interface in the XML format.

GiansantiDesign

Senior Web Developer (Ruby on Rails, React, Angular) January 2015 - December 2017 (3 years)

Syracuse, NY, United States

- Involved in developing Rails-API for the web applications using Ruby on Rails, HTML, XML, CSS, JavaScript, Angular.JS, Express.JS, React JS, and JQuery.
- Worked with varieties of Relational Databases (RDBMS) like SQLite, MySQL, and PostgreSQL and NoSQL DBs like MongoDB.
- Maintained Linux hosting environment, Apache web server and MySQL database server.

eKamria

Web Developer (Python, Django, HTML, JavaScript, CSS) January 2013 - December 2014 (2 years)

Syracuse, NY, United Staates

- Developed virtual assistant applications for major customers. Worked closely with clients through the entire development cycle, gathering requirements, prototyping, implementing, testing, delivering, and supporting the application.
- Created a scalable portable production-ready virtual web chat application.
 Researched, architected, and implemented speech recognition, text to speech, cross-browser compatibility, and reactive design

Netsmartz

Software Engineer

January 2012 - 2012 (less than a year)

Pittsford, NY, United States

- Design, involved in code reviews and wrote unit tests in Python, and updated site with JavaScript, JQuery, Bootstrap, and SQL.
- Helped with the creation of a RESTful API using Python-Flask, integrating with Apache.
- Created Git repository and added the project to GitHub.

Education

Baruch College

Bachelor of Computer Science, Computer Science · (April 2006 - March 2011)